Guide to the Leonard Sidney Rosenfeld Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Leonard Sidney Rosenfeld papers
1935-1990
MS 1360
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
9.75
(12 boxes)
The papers consist of correspondence, diaries, writings, and topical files which document Leonard Rosenfeld's career in the field of public health. The papers highlight Rosenfeld's work for the Institute of Inter-American Affairs in Nicaragua, as vice-chairman of the Health Services Planning Commission for the Province of Saskatchewan, and as associate director of the Community Health Association of Detroit, a group practice prepayment plan established by the United Auto Workers. The papers are part of the Contemporary Medical Care and Health Policy Collection in Yale University Library.
Rosenfeld, Leonard S.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Leonard S. Rosenfeld, 1983; and of Irene Rosenfeld, 1995-1996.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Conditions Governing Access
Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy for their personal use should consult Copying Services information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
Scope and Contents
The papers consist of correspondence, diaries, writings, and topical files which document Leonard Rosenfeld's career in the field of public health. The papers highlight Rosenfeld's work for the Institute of Inter-American Affairs in Nicaragua, as vice-chairman of the Health Services Planning Commission for the Province of Saskatchewan, and as associate director of the Community Health Association of Detroit, a group practice prepayment plan established by the United Auto Workers. The papers are part of the Contemporary Medical Care and Health Policy Collection in Yale University Library.
Automobile industry workers; Health maintenance organizations; Medical care -- Saskatchewan; Public health -- Nicaragua; Labor unions and public health; Health-officers; Physicians; Contemporary Medical Care and Health Policy Collection; Rosenfeld, Leonard S.; Institute of Inter-American Affairs (U.S.); International Union, United Automobile Workers of America (CIO)
- Original accession
  - The Community Health Association, 1957-1958 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Medical manpower and the CHA program, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Development of medical groups, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Medical service areas, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Proposals concerning CHA benefits, 1957-1958 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Principles--CHA relationships with community hospitals, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - CHA organization, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Medical manpower and licensure in Michigan, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - CHA proposals for South Macomb County, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Preiiminary proposal for CHA medical centers, 1958-1959 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - CHA plan of action, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Metropolitan Hospital memo of Understanding, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Progressive care at Manchester Memorial Hospital. Conn., 1958 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Legal status of CHA, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Additional material, 1941-1990; Accession 1995-M-098; 5.25
  - Writings, 1942-1982 (Box 1)
  - Writings, 1983-1990, undated (Box 2)
  - Daily records, 1942-1948 (Box 2)
  - Topical files
    - Queensborough housing report, 1941 (Box 2)
    - Nicaragua, 1943-1948 (Box 2)
      General
      See also: box 5
    - Saskatchewan (Box 5)
    - Methods of studying medical education, 1951 (Box 3)
    - Evaluation studies: Yale conference, 1955 (Box 3)
    - Medical care evaluation studies in Boston, 1953-1963 (Box 3)
    - Medical care evaluation conference, 1956 (Box 3)
    - Research design, 1956, 1969 (Box 3)
    - Program evaluation in medical care, 1959 (Box 3)
    - Approach to program evaluation, 1959 (Box 3)
    - Hudson Bay Mining Employees' Health Association, 1960 (Box 3)
    - Detroit: Metropolitan Hospital and Clinics, 1960 (Box 3)
    - Patient care research, 1961-1980 (Box 3)
    - Latin American Science Board, 1964-1965 (Box 3)
    - Medical audit techniques, 1965 (Box 3)
    - Home health facilities and services in Southern New York; Medicare Evaluation studies; impact of Medicare and Medicaid on utilization of Rome Health Services, 1967-1971 (Box 3)
    - New York City ambulatory case studies, 1967-1968 (Box 3)
    - Puerto Rico, 1967-1975 (Box 4)
    - Clinic studies procedures, 1968-1972 (Box 4)
    - Physicians staff appointments, 1969 (Box 4)
    - American Public Health Association, Program Area Committee on Medical Care Administration, 1966-1969 (Box 4)
    - Center for Ambulatory Care Research, 1969 (Box 4)
    - Regional organization paper, European trip, 1972 (Box 4)
    - Quality assurance, St. Louis, 1973 (Box 4)
    - Costs ofhealth care, 1986 (Box 4)
    - General filing code, undated (Box 4)
  - To be sorted, 1969-1975, undated (Box 4)
  - Scrapbooks
    - Nicaragua, Circa 1942-1946 (Box 5)
    - Saskatchewan, Circa 1946-1948 (Box 5)
- Additional material, 1935-1990; Accession 1996-M-011
  Scope and Contents
  Also includes Accession 1996-M-045, 1996-M-107
  - General files [includes correspondence, reprints, etc.], Circa 1941-1990
    - Correspondence (Box 1)
    - L (Box 1)
    - P (Box 1)
    - T (Box 1)
    - V (Box 1)
    - Arbona, Guillermo (Box 1)
    - Cosin, L. (Box 1)
    - Donabedian, Avedis (Box 1)
    - Goldman, Franz (Box 1)
    - Grant, John B. (Box 1)
    - Molina Guzman, Gustavo (Box 1)
    - Murray, D. Stark (Box 1)
    - Roemer, Milton I. (Box 1)
    - Saclder, Arthur (Box 1)
    - Sheps, Cecil G. (Box 1)
    - Sigerist, Hemy E. (Box 1)
  - Topical files [includes correspondence, writings, notes, printed material, and photographs]
    - Boston, Circa 1955-1962, 1969 (Box 1)
    - Detroit, Circa 1963-1969 (Box 1)
    - New York, Circa 1967-1974 (Box 2)
    - Nicaragua, Circa 1942-1946, 1983 (Box 2)
    - Puerto Rico, Circa 1966-1974 (Box 2)
    - Saskatchewan, Circa 1945-1952, 1988 (Box 2)
    - Saskatchewan, Circa 1946-1948 (Box 3)
    - University of North Carolina, 1972-1981 (Box 4)
    - Venezuela, 1952-1980 (Box 4)
    - Federal aid to medical education, 1946-1948 (Box 4)
    - Hospital appointments, 1948, 1977 (Box 4)
    - Long stay; home health care, 1954-1978 (Box 4)
    - Medical care evaluation, 1954-1959 (Box 4)
    - Multiphasic screening, 1969 (Box 4)
    - Problems in education of public health personnel, 1951, 1964 (Box 4)
    - Regional organization, 1963-1964 (Box 4)
  - Consultations and reports
    - Queensborough morbidity, 1940-1941 (Box 4)
    - Maryland program of public medical care, 1946-1949 (Box 4)
    - Medical care organization, 1940 (Box 4)
    - Medical schools for public health service, 1948-1953 (Box 4)
    - American Public Health Association Subcommittee on Medical Care, 1952 (Box 4)
    - Bingham project, 1954 (Box 4)
    - Rochester regional organization, 1954-1958 (Box 4)
    - Hudson Bay Mining Employees' Health Association, 1960 (Box 4)
    - Discharged hospital patients, 1963 (Box 4)
    - Gouverneur Health Service Program, 1966 (Box 4)
    - Bowery Savings Health Service, 1967 (Box 4)
    - Home care evaluation, NYSNA, 1969 (Box 4)
    - APHA position on national health insurance, 1977 (Box 4)
    - Ball proposal on national health insurance, 1977 (Box 4)
    - Carter national health insurance proposal, 1979 (Box 4)
    - National Council for International Health/Caribbean Community Health Manpower Project (Caricom), 1981-1984 (Box 4)
  - Writings and reprints, 1942-1982, undated (Box 5)
  - Background materials, Circa 1935-1959 (Box 5)
  - Unsorted, 1949-1988 (Box 5)
  - Community Health Association and Metropolitan Hospital, Detroit, 1957-1965 (Box 5)
  - University of North Carolina [farewell from students], circa 1982 (Box 5)
  - "Community Health & Hospitals" [interview for radio broadcast on Showcase WJR Detroit], Circa 1960; audiotape (Box 6)
  - Regionalization study results [Boston area panel], Circa 1958; audiotape (reel-to-reel) (Box 6)
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
    3 3/4 speed, dual track
  - Madison panel, circa 1960; 2 audiotapes (reel-to-reel) (Box 6)
  - Barry Gray program, 1972; 2 audiotapes (reel-to-reel) (Box 6)